what's up guys welcome back to another
african podcast so here we have a very
interesting man that uh this literally
just like popped up out of the blue he
hit me up he's like yo i'm going to
miami we need to do podcasts i'm like
whatever you want man whatever you say
you're the og what's up roger perfect
man good good you're doing good yeah so
how was your flight bro because you're
over in pakistan now so how was yours
yeah yeah it was great 15 hours but but
but we made it through the only thing is
like i had to beat jet lag
right and from for me to be jet lag i
had to make sure that i knew the time in
miami and i knew the time that i'm going
to flying over
right so what do you mean like you stay
up all night before coming yeah like um
from pakistan to doha i stayed up all
night and then once we boarded the plane
from doha
you know i was like okay if i sleep the
first five hours and if i wake up after
five hours that's going to be 9 a.m
miami time
so
once i wake up at my 9 am miami time all
i got to do is wake up land land in
miami stay awake the evening and then go
back to sleep at night
so that's what i did it worked out
perfectly so then it was two flights to
get here it was two flights okay two
flights pakistan
how long was like the whole like flight
was like 22 hours 22 hours but
yeah yeah yeah yeah but but so
we had to choose between
emirates and
qatar
airlines right so people who don't know
business class of qatar is way better
way better and cheaper right what's
cheaper
what's that like how like how much
cheaper i know the flights are like four
or five grand well emirates is going to
be like 6 000 but atar was like 5 500
but they have a q suite like they make
up your bed for you the mattress it was
crazy yeah i've seen the instagram they
look crazy it was crazy because because
like once you sit there they bring you a
hot towel they bring you drinks and then
they say okay
what time do you want your bed made and
i'm like what
did he yeah what time do you want your
bed mate after breakfast or after lunch
i'm like i'm looking at the time i'm
like okay you know what i'm gonna have
breakfast and then after breakfast fine
then maybe walk out the seat and then it
made my bed and look perfect so then you
knocked out like the whole flight yeah
knock out the whole site for for so
this is your first time in miami you
know because i know you were in canada
before or something like that right yeah
so
um
first time i came to miami was in
march 2020 i think that's when i met
raul for the first time too
march 2020. it was funny because that's
when
kovit was like really
out there right so remember i have my
passport in hand walking through
canada canadian customs and uh and they
look at they're like
where are you going no i'm going to
miami he's like what
are you crazy we have a pandemic
happening right now and i'm like oh no
that's fine they're like well why are
you going to miami for i'm like
um to meet some friends they're like oh
yeah
yeah so that was the first time you came
to miami and this is your second time
now it is my second time now but like i
would say this would be my first time
because like the first time i came was
just strictly business friday saturday
sunday we had the boot camp all done but
this time i came on monday
just to experience what miami is like
right because like monday tuesday
wednesday thursday
miami time it's amazing that's fine
there's so much to do yeah right like
like it's just incredible it's
incredible it's like it's like the dubai
of north america really yeah oh yeah
yeah we were probably planning a trip to
dubai maybe like sometime this year and
next year we've never like really like
took that step because that flight is
just like killer we went to cali once it
was like six hours it's a killer flight
yeah
and we're like bro we don't we don't
know if you want to do that so i want to
talk to you about
roger banks before roger banks like like
how did you come into trading how did
you blow up like because you're an og in
the game right like before i started
trading i've seen you like on youtube i
know you started embarrassing me no no
before you you're like you're like a no
g man so like talk to me like like like
how did you make all this like happen
like what the hell
all right if you haven't downloaded the
swing training lab app it's available on
google play store and apple app store
you're missing out it's like my own
version of like a twitter right because
it's a free section and i'll either do
chart breakdowns or free signals or i'll
kind of do like just like psychology
tips on how the market is actively
updated it's like my version of a
twitter so whenever the markets are
going crazy like cpi last week i'm like
guys stay away from cpi or update like
it's like a twitter but for traders
right on my free app make sure to
play store and on download
play store check it out
um so you want the long story or the are
the short story the medium
medium story right in the middle okay
medium story um
high school high school was okay good um
didn't really get good grades at all
that was in pakistan pakistan pakistan
yeah so i did my
all levels which is high school in
pakistan and and then i did my um high
school also
that's
a levels in pakistan and then i went to
university right went to university i
did around maybe like seven semesters in
university computer sciences in pakistan
and then
a turning point happened right my father
my father decided that it's going to be
a great time at this point that he
should apply for business immigration to
canada
right now at this point we didn't know
anyone in canada nobody we didn't we
didn't know a thing all my dad knew that
okay i'm gonna uh apply for immigration
to canada for the whole uh family we're
all gonna go to canada and somehow
we're gonna create a life there
so i'm like
okay perfect canada pakistan to canada
perfect let's do it you know so um we
immigrated to canada
um i did seven semesters in pakistan so
when it came time to transfer my credits
to canada
they transferred maybe one semester wow
right how many years
is i didn't go to college what i have no
idea
okay so so um one semester so in this
it's four years right so four years have
eight semesters oh wow so i did seven oh
[__] i had one left but they accepted
one of them you know they accept one of
them something like okay no problem one
of them i'll deal with that right
and what happened was when we moved over
there now this whole canada culture was
new to me right like partying and this
and that and this is all new to myself
like oh wow crazy so i went nuts with
that you know i went so nuts i couldn't
get grades they were falling grades are
following my my um younger brother so i
was the oldest right my younger sister
she graduated
my younger brother he graduated and then
a point came that my youngest one
she was getting into the same university
where i was in so i was in the third so
i still had like two years left and she
was coming in at that point when she was
coming in i felt like a loser i was like
i haven't graduated yet the youngest one
is coming in i was like yeah no this
can't be so i went to my counselor i
asked him okay how long is it going to
take for me to graduate she's like it's
going to take you three more years
right three more now i'm 26 and i'm
looking at three more years and my
youngest one is in university i was like
this can't be happening to me right
because i'm the kind of guy who's going
to look at that and say you know what no
this is this was a big step to my ego
you know so i was like no um so i talked
to my dad i'm like hey listen i'm going
to quit university and i'm going to go
to alberta because i heard someone in
alberta works drives a truck and he
makes 32 dollars an hour
with overtime
that's what i'm going to do okay
so he's like whoa
okay
you know so so so i i left university i
packed my bags um i remember i had a i
had a
grand am it was a 1999 grand am i don't
know what the hell was that is that a
car do you guys know where grand am's
a car yeah i wasn't born yet i have no
idea i have no idea what that was
i bought for a thousand dollars so
i took that to alberta and uh my first
time in alberta was like okay my whole
plan was i had a thousand dollars with
me
and for that thousand dollars i had to
get a room in a motel
right so now imagine i dropped out of
university
my family thinks i'm a failure because i
dropped a university and i'm moving to
alberta to make money
right and i told them i have a job in
alberta i'm going to go there have a job
they're paying for my food they're
paying for my lodging everything's all
set up but i didn't have [__] all set up
at that point so i went there got a
motel room
uh stayed in the motel for five days it
was like 150 a night and i was running
out of money long story short i found a
guy in red deer alberta he had like a
trailer park he rented me his room so i
got a job over there and i worked there
but that job didn't last for so long you
know and
one
biggest lesson i learned from there was
about not burning bridges
right so
what happened was i got a small job that
job was paying me like 7000 a month
and then i got another offer from a
bigger company that was willing to pay
me 12 000 a month you know so i told you
that's pretty good right that's not
that's not like terrible for like just
coming over out of college right yeah
yeah oh yeah like
when i dropped out of college i googled
highest paying jobs in canada and they
were all in the oil fields
all in the oil fields like no
education needed nothing all in all i'm
okay i'm going to go over there and make
some money so i told the guy hey i'm
going to work for this bigger company he
said we stayed and i didn't stay and
that was the biggest lesson i learned
because once i moved to the bigger
company
there was no work
right it was no work i promised my
family that hey i'm gonna move over to
alberta make money and i want to support
you guys and at that point i remember my
dad he had a leather store
and that leather store in profits was
doing 800 a month 100 800 a month
900 a month profit
so being where i am right now when i
think about that i get goosebumps man i
got [__] goosebumps because 800 a
month to support four kids at the same
time and one is one has just [__] off
to alberta to work and he's not making
any money
that took a big toll on my mind i was
like wow this can't be happening because
this bigger company promised me hours
and money but there was nothing over
there
so i had to move back i sold my car i
sold the grand am for maybe like seven
hundred dollars i took the first ticket
moved back
back to your parents to my parents
you know and my dad was like
like hey like
we gotta go to pakistan can you can you
chip in something i'm like
i can't i don't have anything
you know and and that was the point that
was the lowest point of my life
because that's the point where you feel
like a loser you know you're you're
you're 26 27 years old you're supposed
to make money you're supposed to be
helping your parents out that you can't
you know and at that point i realized
that
burning bridge is why it's not it's it's
so important not to burn a bridge
because i had a consistent income i left
that
got greedy went somewhere else and now i
was learning a lesson
so um so how did you go from nothing to
then learning how to trade well
that same year next year i went back to
alberta
wait so
so your family went to pakistan yeah
yeah yeah yes and you stayed here alone
no no no we we all went to pakistan so
basically what happened was we bought
tickets from our credit cards
right so we chipped in all our cards we
basically put down all our cards we
bought tickets and went back to pakistan
to visit family this and that and um
and then from the and and that's when i
met my wife
right that's when i went met my wife so
we came back to canada and i was like
okay you know what now i'm gonna go back
to alberta because now i have more
experience so maybe maybe it's going to
work right so
that time i went to alberta and i
literally walked into the first office i
remember it was savannah drilling right
i went in the office the receptionist's
name was becky i walked in i'm like hey
becky how you doing and she looked at me
she's like oh hey what's your name i'm
like hey this is raja i was here last
year and you said i needed experience
here's my resume so i affect some
experience on a resume like here's my
resume you know i've been working last
year and this and that some like you
know trying to go out again she looked
at my resume and uh long story short i
got that job on the rigs you know it was
amazing i was making maybe so we were
working 91 hours a week
right 91 dollars so
doing that so i worked there for one
full year you know that one full year
i think the work was maybe eight months
eight months i was making like
seven thousand eight thousand dollars a
month and what i learned was that i'm
making good money
but i'm sacrificing time
like i'm substituting time to make a lot
of money you know and whenever i would
get breaks you know so so what would
happen was you would work two weeks then
you get one week off one week off i'd
come back to ontario because we moved to
on ontario i'd come back and some of my
friends were working door-to-door sales
you know and they were making maybe like
10 12 000 a month working uh less hours
so i would always see that i was like
okay that's interesting because i'm
working this much
making less than them but they're home
at the same time but they're making more
you know so this one time i went back
and i'm like okay hey guys like you guys
got to hook me up what are you guys
doing
you know so they said okay so we sell
stuff door-to-door like hot water
filters you know um hot water tanks
furnaces stuff like that
what they told me that
every sale you make you're gonna make
sixteen hundred dollars every sale and i
was like what
so i saw
i was like what sixteen hundred percent
you know so i told my dad i'm like hey
like you know there's this opportunity
here you know like
whenever something happens i
i go to my dad i'm like hey like you
know what you think of this so he looked
at me he's like listen if this was that
easy
everyone would be selling door-to-door
sixteen hundred dollars a check
you know so i was like no no no like you
know it's real these are young guys they
have an r8 like one one guy barnard this
was like back in 2015. 2015 2014 when
the r8s were new you know you had an r8
you were like oh wow this guy's balling
you know so um
so
i took that opportunity
my parents said no don't do this you
know like the thing is when um when your
family members tell you don't do certain
things but you believe in that you know
you're like oh you're against my hustle
you're against my grind this and that
it's not like they're against your grind
they love you they don't want you to go
through hardships right they don't want
their offspring to go through hardships
go through pain no money and all that
that's why they tell you hey get a
consistent job where you can make enough
money to pay your bills and support
yourself right business entrepreneurship
it's very hard you know that right you
guys know that too it's very very hard
so um i did that sales first month
nothing
nothing no sales no so you didn't
collect no check nothing nothing like
and at that point my wife was living
with me too so imagine like so we would
go out at like 8 a.m
and come back at like 9 00 p.m from 9 00
a.m till 7 p.m we'd be knocking on doors
every day
all day long knocking on doors coming
home at night my parents would ask me
hey you have any sales
my wife would say oh your day went good
i'm like yeah i know nothing so first
month nothing absolutely nothing and
remember
after the first month i got my first
sale
and i knew that from that one sale in my
i walked out i remember this was this
house i walked out and there was this
little uh garden they had and in that
garden they had a bench
i sat on that bench
it was raining a little bit and i
started bawling my eyes out oh wow i
started crying i was like wow i finally
got my first sale the homeowner came out
he's like hey buddy you okay it's
raining
okay no i'm good i'm good my manager is
on his way so he came he took so
from that point i learned i think
door-to-door sales really set me up for
trading
right i'm going to tell you how because
when we're doing door-to-door sales we
had a lot of turnover rate because like
you know you knock on the door you don't
know who's going to answer
right you don't know what type of mood
that guy is going to be in sometimes we
knock on the door the guy would open the
door he's like what do you want you know
or some guys would say oh hey how can i
help you right so every door was
majority of doors were nose
you know knock on the door no we don't
want it don't i don't want it someone
who let us in then that would be a sale
so
when i started trading you know this was
one of our agents he would come into the
office every day and he would say so he
was with this uh mlm company called wfg
i forgot the main name of wfg but it was
called wfg it was a multi-level
marketing before iml
and he would come in and he would show
me his phone he was like hey roger look
look i'm up two hundred dollars those
are probably like demo profits oh yeah
yeah yeah yeah demo number things like
300 400 dollars i'm like okay
great
we have team meeting now
go back to our team meeting right
because we got to go in the field and
make some real money right this demo
shade is not going to work so um that
stayed in my mind that then one day so
so what happened was we had around 20
agents right um business was doing
really well we were doing around
quarter million a year right and so we
had a lot of down time right so one day
i'm sitting i'm scrolling through
instagram
and um
i see this guy
uncle ted
on instagram oh gee as well right i see
this guy uncle instagram and he posted
something about 8 000
in a few trades and i was like i was
looking at that i'm like what i'm like
okay so this kid he showed me his
profits too and this guy is making 8 000
i'm like what is this you know so i
messaged him i'm like hey what's this
he's like um
this is a 4x i'm like oh okay
then uh like you know our agent came
back i asked him more about it he's he's
like yes like meta trader for this and
that so
my whole concept at that time was that
okay i worked on the oil rigs i made
great money but i substituted time right
and then i started go to our sales which
was better money
but i spent less time
right now i was looking at someone who's
making more money but spending less time
so my whole mindset was that okay now
slowly i can probably deviate into
something where i can make more
but um like you know in in less amount
of time so that's what really got me
into trading like you know we had a lot
of downtown downtime had some money
saved up stuff like okay i was looking
for new challenges
right like i met a friend over here in
miami ray he's great businessman real
estate car stuff like that so he's in
the same position now where he's looking
to say okay you know what i got a lot of
time i got to find new challenges in
life you know so that's that was me back
then so so you were chilling in the oil
rigs making enough to maintain your life
maintain your family and then you're
just like let me try this so you just
like did it to just like
entertain it basically just to like okay
let's see if i can do something with it
and then when was the point where you're
like alright like this like you know
forget about the oil rig this is the new
the new thing like how do you know how
to take that leap of faith because i
think that's like where like a lot of
people are just like i have a good
paying job yeah i have a good you know
income but i want better so how'd you
know like how to do that leap if you're
if you're so like nonchalant about it
and then you're doing good at your
ordering yeah if it wasn't
the oil ring that was like you know the
business we had door-to-door right yeah
so the thing is i got very complacent
with my business
it was running on autopilot we had
agents come in they're going through
fields the work they get sales and
whatever you know everything was perfect
so you like leveled up in the ladder now
now you're like you got people under you
like yeah exactly exactly right so so
when it came to trading i was like okay
so so what happened was um so i started
asking questions to ted i'm like this
and that blah blah so i guess at that
time there were a lot of people asking
him questions plus also um
there were other influencers out there
as well from the uk
some from miami too i'm i'm not going to
name everybody but you know so i would
message them saying hey like you know
like what do you think about brokers
which broker i should go to which pair i
should trade and say that and most of
them
like you know what they told me
this is our program
buy this program and you'll get all your
answers
and i'm like what
just didn't make any sense because i was
a business guy right and i thought
everyone would be open to share some
information not the entire information
some knowledge where it could get
me to a right track right but this ted
guy he told me okay go open an account
in ic markets and i said okay like i was
just dumb yeah you know i didn't i don't
know anything about trading i'm like i
see microsoft i opened up an account and
i see markets i i i i asked him how
should i deposit
a credit card or bank transfer and ted
said i don't know man whatever makes you
feel comfortable like okay so deposit a
200 account and uh in one week i lost
that account because easily because i
don't know what i was doing easily you
know so at that point you know ted
answered a lot of my questions
okay you know what this guy is open to
me he's answering everything perfect so
at that point he was having a um hosting
a webinar online webinar so i guess
because like a lot of people were asking
him questions so he wanted to just like
host a webinar it's like a group
something like that it was about 350 you
know so i paid him 350
he lived about 30 minutes away from me
and i told him hey listen if this is a
scam
if you take my money away i know where
you live and he's like he's like yeah
yeah don't worry don't worry you know
something okay so i took his webinar
and um and that was a beginning of a
really really good friendship wow
because what happened was
once that
webinar was done
we used to have zoom um chats every
morning right every morning at around 6
6 30 am we would have a zoom meeting and
in that zoom meeting there'd be like you
know 20 30 of us and we're just looking
at the markets that okay usd cad is out
of support it can go up over here okay
let's take a buy and see what happens
prices go up profits okay prices go down
negative losses we're like okay why why
did we take a loss so that's how we
started like the basics
and then how did ted like like if ted
had so many people hitting
like hitting him up how did you get to
become just like the one that he was
like one-on-one with oh um it's not even
about you know his house in canada
you're like yo where you are
no actually we went to eat tacos okay
and he paid for my lunch so yeah yeah
that was a very very nice of him
you just got to be active yeah you just
got to be outspoken you got to be active
because we had we had i remember we had
like six groups and
you had to be very vocal about what you
were doing sharing charts and stuff like
that like like now you have a group
right you have a group um i have a
group as well so i always say like
whenever you're joining a mentorship
group you're not joining a mentor group
just like sit back and just read the
chat you're not going to fly on the wall
yeah no you can't you have to
participate because the more you're
going to participate people are going to
notice you and the more you participate
the more you post charge the better you
get at the charts because like you know
in the beginning like
a lot of people when they join groups
they're very shy right they don't want
to post analysis because they want to
seem stupid
right because like guys tell me all the
time hey i don't post charts because
there's maybe it's just
it's got a critique yeah exactly like i
don't know if i
did it well or like you know i don't
want to embarrass myself i'm like hey
that's the way to learn you know you
post charts i use support post charts
all the time
all right so we had a little cut there
so so consider what you were saying
basically like you're getting the rhythm
you're the guy always posting the charts
yeah in the chat right because you know
i'm sure we have you know like you can
see like the different type of energy of
people in there in the shot some people
like pop on the zoom they don't even
talk they don't even show their face i'm
sure you're the guy like asking all the
questions so like now that you're like
obviously closer to ted you're getting
on the zooms when did you know how to
have that shift because i feel that's
where like a lot of people get scared
they don't know exactly when to make
that [__] like all right you know what
[__] this business or i'm gonna put it
to the side a little bit more i'm gonna
go full time in trading did you have
like a big trading day did you have just
consistent results like what made you do
that that jump well what happened was um
i think it was a blessing and a curse
because our business was doing very very
well right so i remember we had like
around like 120 130 000 saved up and
i started trading in the mornings right
pre-new york new york time uh just
trading gold one to two trades a day and
then like you know sometimes i would
like drive into the office and i'll be
up like twelve hundred dollars you know
thirteen hundred dollars and to me that
was like oh wow okay i'm up twelve
hundred before the meeting has already
started so i'm like perfect you know
this is probably a means to an end or
probably this is some sort of a side
hustle that may grow to something more
at that point i i didn't really know
much about it
so um
what started to happen was as our agents
would go into work i would still be on
the charts london close noon time 1 pm 2
pm i still be looking at the charts and
once you make profits in the morning and
you start to look at the charts by like
noon 1 pm 2 pm you start to lose those
profits and that's what started to
happen i started to lose profit i
started to trade
um new york close
right new york closed i would take
trades at new york close
pick my agents at 5 p.m when the spreads
get wild yeah you know drawdown was
increased i would drop them off to work
i'd head home at like 7 8 p.m my age in
open i'd be in massive drawdowns yeah
after making profits in the morning i'd
be in drawdown in the evening you know
so that took a huge toll on my
psychology because at the end i was like
okay you know what
um some days i can make two three
thousand but some days i'm losing four
thousand five thousand so i'm like okay
you know what slowly i'm gonna add money
to my account
so i started adding money to my account
you know because i had money saved up
and i was okay you know what i'm the
boss over here i got money saved up i
can just trade you know so my business
started to take a hit you know
the late late 2016
i lost my business
because my agents got poached by other
managers because
door to door is a very competitive
business very competitive if you're not
on top of your agents they're going to
get poached by someone else and they'll
offer them more money so my agents got
poached my business was in a downhill
you know and trading i was just
losing money here and there you know so
but
the first two months of trading
incredible
made amazing profits you know but after
that i started losing start to think to
myself that okay what's happening over
here first two months was amazing then
i'm losing so i looked at my so so i
actually talked to ted i'm like hey man
like
i don't know what's going on i'm losing
my business
you know i'm losing money in trading i
got a family i'm planning a kid soon
like what the [__] is going on over here
he's like look at your pet the only
thing he told me he's like look at your
parents right so i didn't know what
parent to look at we talked patterns you
know like
and then
one night i was sitting and just
watching charts and i remember had a bye
on pound yen
and it was a three lot bye we were
living in an apartment you know my wife
was there with me too and i told her hey
we made 900 in this buy over here but i
was already in a drawdown for my savings
you know
and i looked at that and i'm like okay
you know what
and then ask myself why did i take this
buy and the only reason i know why i
took this buy was because the four-hour
candles were at support and i took a buy
price went up about 30 pips 35 pips i
closed the trade profits i'm like okay
and then an epiphany happened you know
and then i'm like okay so in the
beginning how we used to trade was we
would literally look at
four currencies
usd jpy usd cad
gu and gold
that's it four currencies we would look
at the four-hour candles right and we
would look to see where the four-hour
candles are closing whichever currency
is for our candidate will close at a
support or resistance
we would take a buy or sell secure 10 15
pips and call it a night or call it a
day right now oh okay [__]
this is what we were doing the first two
months i was making crazy profits and
after that what happened was
i want to make more money
you know and the only way to make more
money was to get more pips
100 pips
200 pips 500 pips
looking through instagram oh okay
fibonacci is perfect hundred per trade
let me get that
right let me get that trade well let me
get that ema crossover trade so started
learning about bollinger bands you know
emas fibonacci stochastics rsis i was
doing at one point i was doing
divergence trading based off of macd's
and
stochastics you put those two charts up
and you draw a divergence line and then
you look at the chart and then you try
to trade and tell me how well that goes
yeah it's too much
[__] up man like it didn't went too
well at all yeah yeah you know and and
that's what i did for
seven months and i kept losing because i
thought okay the more i learned oops
yeah [__] up no these lights are very
bright yeah i know because because i was
like okay the more i learn the more i'm
gonna make or the more i'm going to earn
but that was not the case because i was
very successful in my business i was
very successful at my job whatever i did
but that same success doesn't come into
trading this is what we were talking
about to ray ray as well like he's very
successful so we're like okay the same
work ethic is not going to come into
trading
right you can't learn more and earn more
it's just those simple things
you know so i had to go back to the
basics then okay let's go back to the
basics let's go back to just reading the
candles because if you can't read
candles you can't trade
no indicator is going to tell you where
price is going to go if you can't read a
candle the biggest example i can give is
um
let's say you have a pie chart right how
simple is it to read a pie chart pretty
simple pretty simple right the pie chart
says 45
60 you're like okay pie pie this is it
perfect what if i told you
that um hey alex i have this indicator
right you put this indicator on your pie
chart
and then this indicator is going to tell
you what percentage is a certain part
you're going to tell me you're out of
your goddamn mind
i could remove this indicator and i can
look at the pie chart until it's at 40
you know same thing with trading you
know like if you can't read the chart
which is candlestick chart
no indicator is going to tell you where
to enter where to trade and i feel like
something that a lot of people
complicate because they're just like
because we come or at least i come i can
tell you kim as well because you're in
sales the more you work the more you're
supposed to get paid yeah meaning the
more you learn the more things you add
to the chart the more you're supposed to
get paid it's like overtime everybody
knows like oh
you work overtime you get paid extra so
everybody thinks that the extra you put
on the chart you're gonna get more money
or the more time you spend on the charts
the more money you're gonna make and i
feel like that's something just killer
because people don't understand how to
not work to get more money and i feel
like that's something that's insane just
guys bro you have to be on the charts
one hour a day and then you're good
sometimes you don't even have to be on
the charts at all a day yeah i feel like
that that's that's something that a lot
of people like yourself you come back
from a very hard working background
doing sales my family's cuban so it's
the same thing
yeah so it's like it's something that is
you're just not gonna like i can tell
you it but you're not gonna understand
it so what did they think like like your
family is cuban oh bro they they they
they i hated it oh yeah i thought i was
an idiot yeah was like a total idiot bro
you're young too yeah right there you're
young what are you doing at this point
that was a total idiot and so i got like
my first payout when i got my first
payout for my funded account that's
where everything like changed it for me
yeah that's where i just blocked out all
of the noise so you're going through all
these like rough paths like when did
[__] turn for you because i know you
started going on live streams right so
at what point do you decide like if
you're losing how are you going on live
stream so like when did [__] turn for
you
it really turned in 2017 so you're
losing for how long now um i lost all my
savings oh [__] i lost all my savings i
remember this one time
we were living in an apartment the rent
was 1300 now um
throughout my working career i've had
money you know i've had money because
you know i started in different projects
and stuff like that i made great money
but there were certain
periods of time
where i experimented with different
things and for maybe like two three
months i wouldn't have enough money you
know and then i would jump into
something else i make good money and
then you know like up and down so this
one time i remember our apartment rent
was thirteen hundred dollars the 1350
plus parking 50 bucks
you know and um didn't have money to pay
for the rent
you know so i told my wife hey like you
know this month we don't have money to
pay for the rent so we gotta make money
somehow and uh
she proposed well we have our
wedding jewelry which we can sell
and we can pay the rent that way and i
remember
i took her jewelry and i went to four
different pawn shops
right four different pawn shops someone
would say a thousand dollars someone
would say 1100
and for me at that point like 50 bucks
mattered a lot you know and this one guy
he said
you know and i was like how about
13.75
and he's like listen kid take it or
leave it i'm like and then i told him
listen i just need extra 50 bucks so i
can pay the rent with parking and i just
want to get that done so he he looked at
me he saw the uh
he saw the urgency he gave me 1400
you know he gave 1400 3050 went towards
rent and stuff later and i was like okay
you know what
after this
i'm going to give trading one last shot
and if that doesn't work i'm done i'm
not going to focus on this at all
because like you know to sell jewelry
like that to pay rent
oh
as a man that's a huge insult you know
so um
that's what it i think i had maybe like
you know
4 000 i took from somebody and a deposit
in the account it started slowly trading
it because at that point what i said to
myself that okay this is what i'm going
to do right um and this is what i tell
guys now too that if you want trading to
pay for your bills
don't focus on making 10 000 a month 50
000 a month don't focus on that focus on
paying one bill a month
you know what i did was okay you know
what my internet bill is
seventy dollars let's withdraw seventy
dollars a month
you know so once you withdraw seventy
dollars a month that goes towards
internet bill you're like okay trading
is paying for my internet you know once
that gets done you're like okay perfect
now there's no pressure i don't have to
trade enough to pay my rent i don't have
to trade enough to like at that point i
was working somewhere else too just to
pay rent as well you know so long story
short um by the eighth month by mid 2017
i remember i had my biggest withdrawal
you know that was four thousand dollars
i remember my bank account was at
sixteen thousand sixteen thousand two
hundred something i woke up and my bank
account was like 21
100 some dollars i was like wow
i look nice in there wow man you wake up
4 000 comes in your bank account has
crossed 20 000 to me at that point was
like okay okay up to that point
um after losing a lot my bank never went
above 20 000 when that went above the
psychological number 20 000 i'm like
this is real stuff
and that was the point where i started
to take it seriously because if you walk
out there and you tell anyone out there
that hey
my bills
let's say like 200 bills are paid from
the market
it's going to blow their mind let alone
telling them you make ten thousand or
twenty thousand you just tell them i pay
my bills from the market they'll be like
what
and i'm struggling here for what
you know
so to me that was a huge deal i paid my
rent from that four thousand i still had
two thousand left over i'm like perfect
just gotta had the same discipline at
that point just one trade a day in the
morning
actually
i'm gonna lie that wasn't my strategy i
copied that from ted
you know because i remember um we would
have our webinars he would come on in
the morning he would come up at like 7
a.m we'd start the webinar at 6 30 he'd
come up at 7 a.m he would take a trade
until like 8 00 5 8 10 like 10 minutes
after new york opened he'd be like i'm
done for the day then he would just go
away
and we'd be on the webinar till london
closed london closed till london closed
so all day all day most of the morning
you know and i was like okay you know
what this guy's making a lot of money
by just
coming on saying hi taking trade and
just going about his day you know i was
like okay let me copy that and that's
what i did i just copied it just one
trade a day one session focus on one
pair
yen you know gold whatever that is just
cop just just copy what successful
people do
that's all i did you know and slowly
what happened was that you start to
understand how a certain pair is going
to move during a certain time let it be
pre-london london open free new york new
york open you're really going to
understand how that moves and slowly
you're going to be okay you know what i
can execute on this trade or if someone
executes on that you're like okay i know
exactly why he executed on that trade so
then when it starts snowballing for you
after after you started spending less
time on the charts after i
started spending less time on the charts
and then what made you start going live
streaming do you still live stream to
this day yeah yeah yeah yeah now now i
base it so um we started live streaming
in 2018. the whole point was it started
as a joke
you know it started as a joke it was
like okay so we were doing live webinars
every day we're we're winning trades and
we're like wouldn't it be awesome
if someone wore a mask went on twitch
live
and traded just silently like you know
wearing a mask trading
made money and then just through a mask
said made money great day today and
stream
right so that that was how it started
you know as a joke you started on twitch
we started on twitch okay we started on
twitch and then we showed some violent
content on twitch then twitch banned us
right we're like oh [__] twitch banned
us and then we went to mixer mixer is uh
online streaming platform by microsoft
we we went over there and mixer was
banned in a lot of countries so we
didn't get exposure then we're looking
let's go on youtube we went on youtube
blew up
and i think most of my discipline came
from the live streams because
um every day going through live streams
saying the same thing which was
one to two trades a day one session
that's all you had to do and i think
that really instilled the concept of
discipline you know because i as a host
i had to show discipline to people who
were watching me
right and i remember our first live
stream was like
50 people watching us 50 people um a
month from there grew to like 100 people
then 200. i remember when you cracked 1
1 000 random people watching you that's
crazy it's insane yeah you know
like would that put like pressure on you
where you were like mess up or no um it
wasn't a lot of pressure because
we built it up
from the bottom like you know so when
you build it up from the bottom it's
kind of like you know you get used to it
you know so so now we get maybe like you
know six seven thousand people they come
and go into the live stream so now it's
just like now really cut down the timing
because i have kids too i got a family
so now we stream only like monday
wednesday thursday or friday depending
on what's happening so you stream for
how long like 30 minutes an hour no like
one and a half hour and then what do you
do like throughout the rest of your day
like when you're done trading spend time
with the family we
we just started going horse riding we do
that i work out working out you know
like uh we got a dog now and it's just
so like you don't revolve your life
around trading anymore that's where you
started seeing more profits no
not at all and this is a very
interesting conversation i had with josh
a really good friend of mine here he
flew in from washington i guess he's
downstairs somewhere yeah yeah and uh he
was like so um we were sitting having
dinner and he's like man
haitian section and i haven't seen you
pick up your phone and look at the
charts at all i'm like why
why would i want to look at the chart at
a time when i know i'm not going to be
trading
right like if i know i'm going to be
trading in new york session it doesn't
make sense for me to look at like what's
time right now it's almost like you know
9 45
it's a hour and 45 minutes after new
york uh asian open
it serves me no purpose to look at the
chart why am i going to look at the
chart i'm only going to look at the
chart if i know i'm going to be
executing a trade
otherwise there's no point so once you
started doing that everything just
started like snowballing everything just
starts snowballing discipline changes
everything in life would be like the top
three things you could suggest somebody
out there like struggling like raja
banks when you first hit up ted like
what would be like the top three things
you guys suggest top three things yeah
top three things the top first thing
is going to be one or two trades a day
that's very difficult
very very difficult because like you
know let's say you got someone with a
500 account you know you you got
something with the 500 account you're
trading the 500
for you to take one trade or two trades
and make like five bucks that's not
enough
you know because you're a 500 account
and you want to make 10 000 tomorrow
you're like
i gotta do more you know but that's
where
uh working in i would say like working
in the traditional sense and working in
trading are two very different things
because the hard work you do in a retail
store or hard work you do in a company
you get promoted quick you get more
money that way but in trading your hard
work is on your discipline you're going
to take one or two trades and that's it
you're going to study those trades
you're going to see why you took that
trade because his thing once you win a
trade
there's always a better entry you could
have taken because if you take a if you
could have taken a better entry that
means you could have had a bigger gain
if you lost a trade there's always a way
how you could have really lowered down
your loss that's where magic keys comes
in right you can mainly lower down your
loss that way so
that's what happened but like if you
look at it that oh i took two trades i
gotta take more trades i gotta put more
work in the charts more trades
so what would be your other two so that
would be number one would be two one or
two trades
one or two instruments
you know like us 30 gold pound yen just
one
pair and the third one is going to be
just choose one time you want to trade
just one time
don't choose a time when you're at the
gym or at the grocery store that's the
biggest mistake guys make right they'd
be at the gym
doing bench presses
set's done all right let's take a look
at the chart yeah ooh draw down oh [__]
another set let's go you know more
drawdown and no that doesn't work like
that so you gotta choose a session that
matches up with your life
that you know that okay in in your real
life this is the time when you have time
to look at a chart okay but let's say
somebody doesn't have time say somebody
like raja raja in 2013 working all day
what do you suggest to those guys
because those are the guys that want to
know when they take the leap of faith
when like when they make that movement
what would you do
see this is a very tough question it is
it is it's a very tough question and i
get salted and mostly i get this from
people who have families yeah you know
they they work from nine to five they
come home they have a family to take
care of and they basically have their
time the time they have is like maybe 10
p.m and 10 p.m there's no volume there's
no 10 p.m eastern time yeah 10 pm
eastern time there's no volume at that
point so what i tell them is to look at
the dailies or the four-hour candles you
know because
what's special about the four-hour
candles is that
every four-hour candle is going to fall
into a higher volume time
okay right you're gonna have a four-hour
candle that's going to start at 1 a.m
eastern time pre-london and that candle
is going to run until 5 00 a.m eastern
so that's your entire london session so
that's where on the charts you're going
to see a big four-hour candle forming
the next four-hour candle from 5 a.m
eastern it's going to run till 9 a.m
eastern which is going to be a new york
session
right so if you can take a look at those
four-hour candles and say that okay all
i got to do
is to identify where a four-hour candle
is going to go
i think i can trade intercession time
intercession time is where you're
placing a trade in pre-london and you're
letting it run till pre-new york or
taking trade in asian session and until
like you know
like you had a gold cell right
yeah yeah yeah he had a gold sell and uh
like uh last week like when he was helen
gold yeah yeah for guys around the rose
yeah yeah we got here we go
so
there's a lot of pressure you got rose
yeah
so so so then somebody that doesn't have
the
you would just tell them just gotta like
grind it out right you got to stay up
throughout the night or wake up a little
bit earlier just make it happen no mark
up the charts mark but yeah but like
let's say like they're working in nine
to five and you're working 95 and then
they're you know you you're trading
there in new york you just got to make
it happen right like you know figure out
have it on your phone somehow because
like i've when i've done like webinars
i'll see people that they're like in the
office and they'll have like their phone
here on the side like the people like at
work are driving a truck you know you
know you know moving around yeah
before they take the leap of faith of
doing it full-time you suggest them to
just try to make it like try to find the
balance while you're working because
like it's [__] up that at the same
time that the markets move
and there's more like momentum is when
you're working right yes so that's like
annoying yeah like the majority of the
people out there yeah the biggest thing
is mark up your chart and visualize how
you're going to see the next four i can
perform you know and i i can guarantee
90 of the time if you do this for a
month
90 of the time you're gonna accurately
visualize how the four hour candle is
going to form
and once you start to visualize that
then you start to execute from the
second month or the third month you're
like okay you know what
i spent a month watching this one pair
throughout the day on the four hour time
frames and i can accurately say that
these are the days when we have volume
and these are the days when the four
candles are bigger so maybe now it's
time for me to like you know take like a
small position just to test it out you
test it out the second month third month
automatically your confidence starts to
increase and you start to understand
that okay you know what
i
i only have to focus on a four hour time
frame because i'm working i have no time
and this is way more easier but like you
know if you're working you've got a
family scalping and stuff like that's
very hard you can't the biggest
psychology tip you would give out to the
guys out there one to two trades a day
that's it pretty simple it's simple one
two two because that removes everything
else that removes greed fear fomo like
like if you just stop at two you don't
let your emotions get to you when you
take the other traits yeah exactly like
um when i wasn't doing too well i people
don't know this i had a virtual
psychologist
you know i'd go to these reddit forums
and they have these ads off like oh you
need help we can help you blah blah blah
i was losing a lot of money and i was
like what the [__] so i had this virtual
psychologist right and uh
when you lose a lot
you can't tell anyone because you inside
you think that people they may not
understand what you're going through
right but so it's very important so i
told this person online that this is
what's happening blah blah and
this person doesn't know what trading
was right and
this one thing they told me they said
okay they told me that the human mind
can only make one or two emotional
decisions in a day
after they told me that i never went to
that session again because what i
realized was that once you're trading
you're trading with money right and
whenever you make a decision around
money
that's an emotional decision you're
making
so psychologically as humans we can't
make more than two or three emotional
decisions around money once you go past
the third and the fourth that's when you
start looking at things from an
irrational perspective and then you go
into over trading and revenge trading
and things just
things start going
oh yeah exactly like there's no point
after that so
whenever someone asks me what's this
what's the secret sauce i'm like one two
two trades a day
if you stick to that you're gonna have a
great time
if you don't stick to that man you're
going to have a tough time at the
markets and then you're going to stay in
the game long enough to know how to fix
it yeah exactly you're going to stay in
the game long enough fair enough yo
appreciate you raja for coming all the
way from pakistan ali over here
appreciate you yeah man thank you thank
you appreciate it so are you guys ready
you know stick to one to two trades a
day and then um easier said than done
easier than that yeah appreciate see you
guys in the next episode